A Guide to the Papers of Ann Beattie
Special Collections, University of Virginia Library
Special Collections, University of Virginia Library
Papers of Ann Beattie 1963-1999
Special Collections, University of Virginia Library
10414-ac,-ad
This collection consists of ca. 1500 items.
Administrative Information
Access Restrictions
Stored off-site. Users must request boxes 48 hours in advance of desired use. Neither drop-in nor next-day requests can be fulfilled. For additional information, contact Special Collections.
Acquisition Information
This collection was deposited 1999 May 4 and June 21
Scope and Content Information
Papers of Ann Beattie include manuscripts by Beattie and others, correspondence, reviews, proofs, miscellaneous publication material and books and other printed pulications.
The collection contains typescripts of Alex Katz, Another you, My life, starring Dara Falcon, and Picturing Will, together with proofs for My life.
Manuscripts by other authors include Dear diary by David Frankel; The little dancer, by Aan Kingsberg; A quarter turn, by Debra Nystrom; poetry from The red house, by Gregory Orr; Anthracite Country by Jay Parini; articles and essays by William F. Ryan; and an article by Tom Wolfe.
Contents List
- Series I: Book Manuscripts by Ann Beattie
  - Alex Katz n.d., Typescript (Box 1)
    w/author's changes and corrections
  - Another You n.d., Spiral Bound Typescript (Box 1)
    previously titled Phantom Pain, w/changes and corrections, and comments by the editor
  - Another You n.d., Typescript (Box 1)
    previously titled Second Growth Pine(4 folders)
  - Another You n.d., Typescript (Box 1)
    w/author's changes and corrections (3 folders)
  - My Life, Starring Dara Falcon n.d., Typescript (Box 1)
    Typescript (2 folders)
  - My Life, Starring Dara Falcon n.d., Spiral Bound Typescript (Box 1)
  - My Life, Starring Dara Falcon 1997 Feb 7, Page Proofs, Master Set, Second Pass (Box 1)
    (2 folders)
  - Picturing Will n.d., Typescript (Box 1)
    w/author's changes and corrections (1 of 3 folders)
  - Picturing Will n.d., Typescript (Box 2)
    w/author's changes and corrections (2 of 3 folders)
- Series II: Manuscripts by Other Authors
  - "Dear Diary" by David Frankel 1995 Aug 21, Typescript (Box 2)
    First Draft of a half-hour pilot
  - The Little Dancer n.d. (Box 2)
    screen adaptation by Alan Kingsberg
  - "A Quarter Turn" by Debra Nystrom n.d. (Box 2)
  - Poetry by Gregory Orr, published as The Red House1979 (Box 2)
  - Poetry by Jay Parini, titled "Anthracite Country" 1978 (Box 2)
  - Articles & Essays by William F. Ryan 1974-1982 (Box 2)
  - Article by Tom Wolfe in The New York Herald Tribune1965 Apr 11 (Box 2)
- Series III: Correspondence & Miscellaneous Papers
  - Articles by Ann Beattie 1976-1999 (Box 2)
  - Books Covers & Jackets ca. 1978-1990 (Box 2)
  - Contracts & Agreements 1974-1998 (Box 2)
  - Correspondence 1973-1998, n.d. (Box 2)
    (4 folders)
  - Correspondence re Job Search 1974-1975 (Box 2)
  - Interviews w/Ann Beattie 1979-1991 (Box 2)
  - Miscellaneous Papers 1963-1999 (Box 2)
  - Papers re Workshops, Conferences & Other Events 1980-1999 (Box 2)
  - Photographs n.d. (Box 2)
  - Printed Material 1973-1996 (Box 2)
  - Publicity Tours & Appearances 1979-1998 (Box 2)
  - Reviews 1976-1998 (Box 2)
  - Reviews of Alex Katz1987 (Box 2)
  - Reviews of Falling in Place 1980-1984 (Box 2)
  - Reviews of Love Always1985 (Box 2)
  - Reviews of Secrets and Surprises 1978-1979 (Box 2)
  - Short Stories by Ann Beattie ca. 1978-1993, n.d. (Box 2)
  - Short Stories published in The New Yorker 1977-1986 (Box 2)
  - Published Books and Printed Publications ca. 1976-1997 (Box 3)
- Miscellaneous
  - Drawing of Ann Beattie by David [Wiegand?] [1980?]
  - Book Jackets for Another You, My Life, Starring Dara Falcon, and Park City(proof) ca. 1995-1998
  - Proofs for three different "Talk of the Town" articles in The New Yorker 1981-1982